# Kurt Taylor, PhD

## **Analyst**

♥ Bristol and Long Eaton, UK \$+447425608190 % www.kurttaylor.io

kurt.taylor20@gmail.com

in LinkedIn

GitHub

Twitter

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### Analyst

#### Delta Hat Ltd

February 2023 - Ongoing

**♀** Long Eaton, UK

 Providing technical and analytical support to the pharmaceutical industry. The company focuses on the technical aspects of evidence-based medicine and health technology assessment.

# Senior Research Associate in Medical Statistics and Health Data Science

#### **Bristol Medical School, University of Bristol**

February 2022 - February 2023

Pristol, UK

- 12-month postdoctoral position conducting analyses of population-based studies linked to extremely large population-level datasets based on electronic health records.
- Developed skills in programming, statistical analyses, project management, using GitHub to collaborate and manage projects, data visualisation and scientific writing.

#### Co-Founder and Event Co-Director

#### **Bristol Track Club**

August 2018 - Ongoing

- Pristol, UK
- Co-founded training group and running events brand based in Bristol (Website).
- Gained experience in: events management and coordination, people management and building a brand.

#### **Doctoral Candidate**

#### **Bristol Medical School, University of Bristol**

September 2017 - February 2022 ♥ Bristol, UK

- Highly competitive 4-year PhD programme funded by the British Heart Foundation. Learned to effectively manage projects and tasks on my own as well as forming several collaborations internally and internationally.
- Received formal training in: Epidemiology, Statistics, Coding (R, Linux and command line tools) and gained experience in: working with and quickly adapting to different teams, project management, presenting/public speaking.

#### Freelance Medical Writer

#### **Aspire Scientific**

## August 2019 - December 2020

**♀** Remote

 As a freelance medical writer, I helped produce a diverse range of high-quality scientific materials. This role often had strict deadlines and required me to work on topics I had no prior knowledge of.

# **SUMMARY**

Highly motivated Epidemiologist / Health Data Scientist with 5+ years of experience working with large complex datasets. Strives to maintain key working philosophies of quality, efficiency and consistency. Experienced in coding (particularly using R for statistical analyses and data visualisation), project management, public speaking and writing for a wide range of audiences.

## **EDUCATION**

#### PhD, Epidemiology

University of Bristol, Bristol, UK

BSc, Sport & Exercise Science - First University of Surrey, Guildford, UK

## September 2014 - July 2017

# **SKILLS**

- General: Statistics, Programming, Data Viz, Project Management, Public Speaking, Writing (scientific and lay), Student Supervision, Collaboration
- Programming / Software (Proficient): R, GitHub, Microsoft Office, Linux & Command Line Tools
- Programming / Software (Familiar): SQL, Stata, Python, LaTeX, Shell Scripting

# ACADEMIC PUBLICATIONS

For a list of my academic publications please see my Academic CV or check out my Google Scholar Profile.

# **AWARDS**

 University of Bristol Open Research Prize for Increasing Research Quality (2021)